dicksmith.com.au 2016-06-14

# Privacy Policy

## Respecting your privacy

Dick Smith Electronics Pty Limited (Receivers and Managers Appointed) (Administrators Appointed) and all its subsidiaries understand the importance of protecting your right to privacy of your personal information. We have policies and appropriate procedures in place to ensure that all personal information, no matter how or where it is obtained, is handled sensitively, securely, and as required by the law. We are committed to adhering to the Australian Privacy Principles (APP), which set clear standards for the collection, access, storage and use of personal information, which may be obtained as part of our business operations.

## What personal information do we collect and store?

When used in this policy, “personal information” has the meaning as outlined in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). Personal information generally includes any information that can be used to personally identify you in order to provide goods and services to you.

  * name;
  * residential or business address including post codes;
  * telephone number;
  * email address;
  * age and date of birth;
  * gender;
  * proof of identity, such as drivers licence or passport;
  * signature;
  * social media information obtained via our Facebook, Twitter, or Instagram accounts;
  * a photograph, image or sound recording of you collected via CCTV surveillance if you visit our stores; or
  * employment history, eligibility status to work in Australia, referee details, and information provided by your referees, whom you have authorised us to contact.

## Other Information

When you buy post-paid, pre-paid mobile phones and SIM cards from us, you will need to provide us with your name, residential or business address, email address and telephone number. In addition to this, we will ask you to give or show us additional information, including proof of identity details such as a Credit Card, Debit Card, Medicare Card, Drivers Licence, or Passport, the mobile phone’s International Mobile Station Equipment Identifier (IMEI) number and SIM card details.   
If you choose not to provide us with the information, we will not be able to provide pre-paid or post-paid mobile servicers our services, such as selling post-paid plans with mobile handsets, or SIM cards to you.   
You can purchase mobile phones outright without providing your personal information, however, we will still collect the mobile phone’s IMEI number during the sale.   
We may also collect information from you that is not personal information because it does not identify you personally. This information is normally retained with your personal information and may include: 

  * • your shopping preferences and a list of goods and services you have purchased from Dick Smith, your shopping and browsing history, product types, specifications, dimensions or other attributes of goods and services we have provided to you or may provide to you in the future;
  * • information we require to deliver, service or fulfil warranty obligations for goods or services;
  * • your marketing preferences, including the type of marketing materials you wish to receive and the method of delivery (email, SMS, direct mail, or other); or
  * • information you provide to us via our customer service centre, website, application forms, or directly to team members within our stores in relation to our goods and services.

## Online Services

We commonly use online services such as websites, for example, dicksmith.com.au, smart phone apps, email, IPTV, Electronic Digital Marketing (EDMs), and social media profiles for the purposes of providing information and services to individuals. Technologies that may be used by us include cookies, web beacons, Flash local stored objects and JavaScript (‘Dick Smith Online Services’). These technologies are used consistently across various services, allowing us to better understand you and provide a more consistent experience across these services.   
When you interact with Dick Smith Online Services, other information which may be recorded includes software versions you are using, your IP address, information regarding location (if this is not disabled), dates, times, file metadata, data which you have entered and user activity such as links you have visited.   
Dick Smith Online Services are operated by us, and by other companies authorised by us to deliver a reliable experience, and to enable you to have a unique experience when using our services and provide direct marketing.   
We will take reasonable steps to ensure that we keep our Privacy Policy updated to keep you informed of any changes we may adopt regarding how we deal with your personal information. We recommend that you visit our Privacy Policy from time to time when using our Dick Smith Online Services, to keep up to date with any changes. 

## Cookies

When you browse websites maintained by Dick Smith Online Services, information about your activity may be stored on your computer in a file known as a “cookie”. A cookie allows our servers to identify and interact more efficiently with your computer device by: 

  * • maintaining the continuity of your browsing session (e.g. if you are looking at multiple products on our website); and
  * • remembering your details and preferences when you return.

Our cookies do not store personal information that can be retrieved to identify you.   
You can configure your web browser to reject and delete cookies and block JavaScript, however, this will limit your ability to interact with Dick Smith Online Services.   
You can also control your activity preferences regarding Adobe Flash, local shared objects (LSOs). You can find out more [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). 

## Why do we need to collect your personal information?

The personal information that we ask for is generally used to provide goods or services to you, or to enable you to participate in our business activities, including: 

  * • creating and fulfilling orders, including pre-orders, Click & Collect orders, home deliveries, providing you with order status updates, transaction records, agreements for the sale of goods or services and tax invoices;
  * • fulfilling our obligations to you for the goods and services that you have purchased or requested from us;
  * • complying with any applicable laws, regulations and directions given by regulators or government authorities, in connection with legal proceedings; investigation and/or prosecution of criminal or fraudulent activities. We are required to collect your personal information if you trade-in your product, or if you purchase from us pre-paid mobile telecommunications services, in order for us to be compliant with the relevant law;
  * • providing your personal information to third parties who assist us in providing goods and services you have requested, such as third party service providers;
  * • advising you of new goods and services, including for marketing and re-marketing purposes;
  * • enabling you to take part in competitions and promotions and notifying you about competition results and special offers, which might interest you;
  * • communicating and responding to questions and complaints raised and to provide you with information or advice;
  * • administering marketing, budgeting, fraud and loss prevention activities, procurement & development of goods and services to continually bring you the best goods and services that can be provided by Dick Smith; or
  * • assessing your suitability for a role you are applying for, if you are a seeking employment, we collect information to assist with the recruitment and selection process.

## Who do we disclose your personal information to?

In order to provide you with superior goods and services, we may need to disclose your personal information to third parties. As such your personal information may need to be disclosed to: 

  * our employees, contractors or service providers;
  * internet and mobile service providers that you have requested;
  * IT systems administrators, mailing houses, couriers, and payment gateway providers;
  * business advisors such as accountants, auditors, lawyers or other professional service providers;
  * suppliers, marketplaces (including eBay, David Jones, TradeMe, Catch of the Day, Mac1, Acer, Groupon);
  * employment agencies where your job application has not come directly via Dick Smith to assist with the assessment of you application;
  * in connection with law enforcement activities to any person authorised by such law from police services, ambulance services, government departments, regulators or authorities; and/or
  * other third parties with whom we have commercial relationships, for business, marketing and related purposes.

Dick Smith takes measures to ensure your personal information is protected from unauthorised access, loss, misuse, disclosure or alteration. We also take measures to destroy or permanently de-identify personal information when it is no longer required. The types of measures we take vary with the type of information, and how it is collected and stored.   
You have the right to tell us that you do not want us to send information to you other than for the main purpose for which we have collected your personal details and we will not share, sell, or disclose your information other than as described in this Privacy Policy.   
Where possible, we try to ensure that our disclosure of information to other organisations (for example market researchers, and others with whom we have commercial arrangements) are in a way which does not personally identify individuals.   
Under the APP, it is our duty to inform you about our disclosure of personal information to any overseas third parties and service providers in order to provide you with goods and services that you have purchased or requested from us.   
We may disclose personal information to overseas recipients in the following countries: 

  * • our related entities in New Zealand and Hong Kong for the purposes of sharing information for general data and product management purposes;
  * • the Philippines for the purposes of customer support and complaint handling;
  * • Singapore for database management in connection with our Clever Dick services which includes providing installation and onsite support and related services;
  * • The United Kingdom for payment processing of online orders; and/or
  * • • The United States of America for database management services in connection with our email marketing, data management programs and customer engagement services;

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that all third parties and service providers do not breach the APPs relating to the personal information you have provided. 

## If we are unable to collect your personal information

  * • Generally, you have no obligation to provide any information requested by us. If you choose to withhold requested information we may not be able to provide you with the goods and services that depend on the collection of that information, particularly if the collection of that information is required by law;
  * • we may be unable to contact you to provide information about goods and services that you have purchased or requested from us;
  * • we may be unable to tailor the content of our marketing communications and thereby impacting your experience when shopping with us;
  * • you may experience delays or inefficiencies when interacting with us as we do not have all the relevant information at hand; or
  * • if you are seeking employment with Dick Smith, we may not be able to process your application.

## Access to and correction of your personal information

We will provide you with access to any of your personal information we hold (except in the limited circumstances recognised by privacy law). We will also provide you with an opportunity to correct any of your personal information that we hold. If you require access to, or if you need to correct details of your personal information, please email [privacy@dicksmith.com.au](mailto:privacy@dicksmith.com.au).   
To help us to properly identify you, we will require some proof of identity. For most requests, your information will be provided free of charge, however we may charge a reasonable fee if your request requires a substantial effort on our part.   
If you need to update your information (eg. if you change your address), please contact the relevant part of Dick Smith to which you supplied that information so we can make the change. 

## Complaints

If you would like to make a complaint about the way your personal information has been handled, or if you think that we have breached our obligations under the APP, you may direct your concern to the Privacy Officer by emailing [privacy@dicksmith.com.au](mailto:privacy@dicksmith.com.au).   
Our Privacy Officer will endeavour to resolve your complaint within a timely manner, and deal with your complaint as follows: 

  * • Acknowledge receipt of your complaint and provide you with a reasonable timeframe for resolving your complaint;
  * • Liaise with relevant departments within Dick Smith, who may assist in resolving your complaint; and
  * • Provide you with our reasoning of how your complaint has been dealt with.

If we are unable to resolve your complaint, we will advise you to make further inquiries, or make a complaint directly with the Privacy Commissioner.   
More information about Privacy law and the APP is available from the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner at [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/)

## Changes to this Policy

We may update this policy from time to time. The most recent version will be posted on our website and our Privacy Policy was last updated on 29 October 2015.
